<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>/eulercoder.me/</title>
   
   <link>/eulercoder.me/</link>
   <description>A place for Eulercoder Community, all about internships, jobs, interviews and some motivation</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ Eulercoder ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ A place for Eulercoder Community, all about internships, jobs, interviews and some motivation ]]>
   </description>
   <link>/eulercoder.me/</link>
   <image>
   <url>/eulercoder.me/assets/images/favicon.png</url>
   <title>Eulercoder</title>
   <link>/eulercoder.me/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="/eulercoder.me/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>College and low GPA: Everything you need to know.</title>
	  <link>/eulercoder.me/2017/08/college-low-gpa-know-everything</link>
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-08-11T12:25:29+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/eulercoder.me/2017/08/college-low-gpa-know-everything</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Many students ask us questions related to college and low GPA. Students with low GPA or those who are in tier three colleges, hesitate in applying for jobs or internships. In this article, we will be discussing and analyzing everything related to college and GPA, its benefits and importance. Also, we will be discussing, whether having a low GPA affect your chances of getting an internship or a job. So let’s get started!</p>

<h1 id="college-and-gpa-benefits-and-importance">College and GPA: Benefits and importance</h1>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>As companies get tons of resumes for every single job/internship, GPA is <strong>just a criteria </strong>for them to shortlist candidates. </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>It is impossible for companies to interview every single candidate, so companies use GPA as a yardstick to shortlist profiles.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>It is generally seen that students from top colleges get higher preference over students from tier two or three.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>If someone is studying in MIT or Standford then definitely he/she will get higher preference over someone who is studying in Mumbai University in India.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reputed colleges and higher GPA shows that student has worked hard to get into a college and he was very punctual in college.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<!-- more -->

<p>[clickToTweet tweet=”Your GPA is NOT going to feed you. What will do that is you practical skills.” quote=”your GPA is NOT going to feed you. What will do that is you practical skills. “]</p>

<h3 id="few-things-to-remember-if-you-have-low-gpa">Few things to remember if you have low GPA</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>GPA will only help you through campus placement that is during your first job only. Once you get your first job, no one will ask your GPA ever again.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What matters at the end is your experience, your practical skills.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>If you have low GPA but you have many co-curricular achievements and good projects, you can easily get shortlisted for any company. In this case, both have equal chances of getting shortlisted.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I had 2.2/5 GPA, I got the internship at Slack and then full-time offer.**  Read:** <a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/slack-amazon-mozilla-linkedin-interview/">My interview experience with Slack, Mozilla, BrowserStack, LinkedIn, and Amazon</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Smart people can always get a good career - higher GPA not. </p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>[clickToTweet tweet=”Remember A 2.0 student can know more than a 4.0 student. Grades don’t determine intelligence, they test obedience. “ quote=”Remember A 2.0 student can know more than a 4.0 student. Grades don’t determine intelligence, they test obedience. “]</p>

<h4 id="complete-python-bootcamp-go-from-zero-to-hero-in-python">Complete Python Bootcamp: Go from zero to hero in Python</h4>

<h5 id="we-have-partnered-with-udemy-for-discount-and-offers-on-different-courses-get-upto-92-off-on-the-ultimate-course-on-python-using-our-links">We have partnered with Udemy for discount and offers on different courses. Get upto 92% off on the Ultimate Course on Python using our Links.</h5>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>[
	
		
		Enroll Now!		
](https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=WQz2hZgW0To&amp;mid=39197&amp;u1=eulercoder&amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.udemy.com%2Fcomplete-python-bootcamp%2F)
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="final-tips-to-get-an-engineering-job-and-internships-with-low-gpa">Final tips to get an Engineering job and internships with low GPA</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Don’t Mention your GPA: </strong>If you have low GPA, leave it off. Do not mention your GPA in your resume. The hiring manager knows missing GPA means low GPA but leave it off anyway.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Demonstrate Practical Knowledge: </strong>Having great projects on your resume, contribution to Open Source Projects, a solid Github profile (See my Github), relative internships, good co-curricular activities, competitive programming, hackathons etc. All these things are extremely important to get shortlisted and by having these things on your resume will definitely make you ahead of the competition. As we all know that Practical knowledge matters the most. Many students are great in schools/universities but can not translate the same in their practical outputs.<br />
[clickToTweet tweet=”Knowledge and Experience will always trump superficial GPAs. “ quote=”Knowledge and Experience will always trump superficial GPAs. “]</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Apply to small companies/Startups first: </strong>All the big companies receive tons of resumes and they use specific tools and algorithms to filter out candidates based on keywords. Recruiting team in big MNCs don’t have time to go through every single resume so it’s better to apply to small companies and startups first. They get fewer applications compared to MNCs and you will have higher chances of getting noticed.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Focus on Resume format: </strong>Make sure your resume is free from grammar, spelling and formatting errors. <strong>Use bullet points </strong>and <strong>highlight experience and achievements. </strong>We highly recommend you to read our <a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/summer-internship-ultimate-guide/">Summer Internship: The Ultimate Guide</a> for best resume tips. You can also use my resume format mention in the guide.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Network: </strong>Networking is extremely important in getting a good job. You have lower GPA, you may need referrals, the recruiter needs to know your skills and strength. Attend different on-campus placements sessions, go out of your way to talk to recruiters. When you and talk to engineers/recruiter, you create and control the very first impression - not your resume (your GPA).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Talk to people on LinkedIn groups, connect with people on the internet (Facebook), show them your work, ask for help. Start a conversation, build a rapport with them, ask for a referral before applying to a job in their company.</p>

<h3 id="lastly-dont-give-up">Lastly, Don’t give up.</h3>

<p>Persistence and patience pay off. I was rejected from 12 companies straight before getting shortlisted for 8 companies. You need to keep improving your skills and your resume. Once you have gotten your first engineering job, all future job and promotions will be based on your work experience. The only time your GPA will come up again is if you are applying to your graduate job. (Not happening ever again :p)</p>

<hr />

<p>What do you think about college and low GPA? Does it really matter? Have you secured a job/internship without mentioning your GPA on the resume? Share your experiences below in comments.</p>

<p><strong>Have something to talk about? Want to contribute in our <a href="http://eulercoder.me/about">Mission and Goal</a>? Write on Eulercoder. Write an <a href="mailto:hi@eulercoder.me">email to us</a> or <a href="http://eulercoder.me/contact">contact us</a> for guest posts. </strong></p>

<p>Did you found this article useful? Write your comments below. 🙂</p>

<p>If you found this article useful, do share with your friends. Let’s help everyone in getting a better internship, job and help them in learning programming. Subscribe to our newsletter and get weekly curated content directly in your mail box. Also, we have our own group on FB, we take Q&amp;A, post materials in the group. I’ll highly recommend you to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/eulercoder">join our FB Group.</a></p>

<p> </p>

<h2 id="subscribe-to-our-mailing-list">Subscribe to our mailing list</h2>

<ul>
  <li>indicates required</li>
</ul>

<p>Email Address *</p>

<p> </p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Three Internships mandatory for Engineering Students: Analysis and Discussion</title>
	  <link>/eulercoder.me/2017/07/three-internships-mandatory</link>
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2017-07-27T16:27:45+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/eulercoder.me/2017/07/three-internships-mandatory</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Education Minister of India announced today that every engineering student has to undergo minimum three internships. I am glad that Education minister is thinking about the unemployment. As per the reports, 80% of engineering graduates in India are “unemployable”. This definitely tells that our Education system needs to be revamped and training system of the teacher and students needs to be upgraded. Internships definitely help a lot in becoming a better engineer. It gives you exposure to the real world things, one good internship can be easily compared with four years of Engineering. Regarding today’s announcement about three internships, the very first thought that came into my mind was, this is going to be very tough for engineering colleges to provide internships to students. Let’s analyze it in this article.</p>

<h2 id="total-engineering-colleges-in-india">Total Engineering colleges in India:</h2>

<!-- more -->
<p>As per the report, there are more than 6500+ engineering colleges in India. The total number of engineering seats in India is around 15,00,000+. So, there are 6500 colleges and if we take an average of total students in any engineering college, considering one college is offering four branches and one branch has up to 60 students. If we do the match, 6500 * 4 * 60 = 15,60,000 students. This means around 15 Lacs students take admission in engineering colleges every year.</p>

<h3 id="15-lac-students-will-be-looking-for-internships">15 Lac students will be looking for internships</h3>

<p>Now, in the first year of engineering, rarely any student does an internship. They just start the four-year degree course without any prior knowledge of programming.</p>

<p><strong>Extra Read:</strong> <a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/what-is-the-ideal-time-to-apply-for-internships-and-jobs/">What is the ideal time to apply for an internship?</a></p>

<p>In the second year, we learn about C, Java, Data Structures, Algorithms and about Web development. The education minister said it will be college’s responsibility to provide internships to students. So, now every student and college faculty also will ask students to start looking for internships after the second year. Consider there are at least 240 students in an engineering college, out of them 40 secured internships on their own. For a college helping 200 students internship in different companies and startups is going to be a tough task. Competition for getting an internship will increase as everyone will be worried about the internship, career, and job.</p>

<h3 id="rise-of-training-companies">Rise of training companies</h3>

<p>You must be knowing about the training companies, they provide training to new employees, take interns, give them big projects for a particular duration, pay a lower stipend (sometimes it’s unpaid internship) and assign them mentors who are mentors just for the name of it. Friends, this happens a lot, there are hundreds of training companies which are doing this only. In India, people always find a way to fool the system. These training companies will increase and maybe to maintain college’s reputation and show government best results, colleges may contact these companies and ask them to visit colleges.</p>

<p>I am not saying this is very bad. It is good, rather than sitting at home you will be doing something to improve your own skills. I am talking from the business point of view.</p>

<h3 id="if-i-have-just-two-internships-in-my-resume-will-this-affect-me">If I have just two internships in my resume, will this affect me?</h3>

<p>No, I don’t think so. For a company, your skills and how you perform in the interview is all that matters the most. Yes, having two or more internships and good projects will definitely help you a lot to get shortlisted. You will have higher chances of getting an interview than those with one internship only. Again, there are so many factors, it will depend on the company you interned, your role there, how solid if your personal projects etc. I am not going into too many details. You can read my <a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/summer-internship-ultimate-guide/">summer internship guide here which is recommended by over 1000+ students</a> on the web and it is one of the top guide available currently.</p>

<h3 id="to-the-students-who-will-be-starting-their-engineering-course">To the students who will be starting their Engineering Course</h3>

<p>If you are going to start your engineering course very soon starting next month. I’d say do not worry about this right now. This is not going to be implemented very soon, so don’t panic. You are just starting your engineering, enjoy the beginning, do networking, take part in events and **learn to program. **Work on your programming skills in your second year, solve problems on Hackerrank or CodeChef. Try open source development. Try everything and find your love for something and do it well.</p>

<p><strong>Read:</strong> <a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/competitive-programming-open-source/">Competitive Programming or Open Source: Which one to choose?</a></p>

<p><strong>Try for internships after:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Competiton of your 2nd year (Summer Internship)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Winter internship for 5-6 weeks after 5th semester (Mid of 3rd year)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Summer Internship at the end of your internship.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>You will have to plan and work accordingly.</p>

<h3 id="conclusion"><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>

<p>This is going to be tough for colleges and students as well to get three internships. Governments SWAYAM portal, which is just launched for free online courses, is also not that good. It is a platform for teachers to sign up for courses and learn there about new technologies. College and students will keep struggling about it and there will be these training companies which will benefit from it.</p>

<p>What do you think about the announcement? If you agree with me and just say yes or comment down below and we will have an open discussion about it.</p>

<p>Thank you!</p>

<p>** My Story **</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/slack-amazon-mozilla-linkedin-interview/">Slack, Amazon, LinkedIn, Browserstack, Mozilla - My Internship Interview Experience</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://eulercoder.me/2017/07/slack-internship-sf-silicon-valley/">Summer Internship, San Francisco, and Silicon Valley</a>
<!-- more --></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>Eulercoder is a platform for everything related to computer science. We weekly send emails with our top articles directly in the mailbox. Subscribe to Eulercoder to get latest updates in engineering and computer science. Lastly, we have a closed <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/eulercoder">group on Facebook</a>, join in to discuss issues, queries, tutorials, anything related to CS.</p>

<h2 id="subscribe-to-our-mailing-list">Subscribe to our mailing list</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>indicates required</p>

    <p>Email Address  *</p>
  </li>
</ul>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
